Jolly Folly Holiday Rampage
Santastein is a horror, comedy, fantasy film directed by Manuel Camilion.
When Max Causey was six, he accidentally killed Santa.
12 years later, Max rectifies his mistake by resurrecting him, but soon realizes the creature he
created is a bloodthirsty killer and it's headed right to his friend's Christmas party.
Max Causey, played by Jared Korotkin.
Paige Byers, played by Ophelia Rivera.
Santastein, played by Michael Vitovich.
Mikayla, played by Kaylie Heyner.
Edgar, played by Damien Edwards.
Katie, played by Heather Fisch.
As of January 2026, a body of 469 known feature films, 236 short films, 93 TV series and 394 TV episodes feature some version or interpretation
of the character Frankenstein's monster, first created by Mary Shelley in her 1818 novel Frankenstein; or, The Modern Prometheus.
The first film adaptation of Shelley's novel was
Frankenstein, a short 1910 film directed by J.
Searle Dawley.
It was followed by Life Without Soul (1915) and Il mostro di Frankenstein
(1921), both of these films are currently considered lost.
The Frankenstein Trestle (1899) was the first film to use the word Frankenstein in its title, although it
was not connected to the novel and showed a train crossing a trestle in the White Mountains.
The 1818 novel describes the creature's appearance as follows:
His yellow skin scarcely covered the work of muscles and arteries beneath; his hair was of a lustrous black, and flowing; his teeth of a
pearly whiteness; but these luxuriances only formed a more horrid contrast with his watery eyes, that seemed almost of the same colour as the dun white sockets in which they were set.
Frankenstein's monster has appeared in many forms
and inspired many similar characters.
It has been gender-swapped, made into an animal,
and given different personalities.
Certain thematic elements remain, such as abandonment, the desire to be loved, and
a dynamic love or hate relationship between creator and creation.
The 1931 film Frankenstein by Universal Pictures and its 1935 sequel, Bride of Frankenstein, have had an
immense influence on the appearance and wider cultural understanding of the character.
This rendition of the creation is the most pervasive and appears
in pop culture and advertising very frequently.
While the imagery of Frankenstein's monster in relation to the Universal appearance is inspired by Frankenstein, it is also frequent that
characters of this appearance lack any relation to the novel and depart heavily from the themes and personality of the original work.
Nevertheless, characters made in the likeness of the Universal Monster are still Frankenstein's
Monster, even if the only likeness is to a pastiche version of the character.
On the other hand, some characters such as Mewtwo and Stitch exhibit similarities in
personality, plot, and shared themes despite their lack of physical similarity.
The films listed here tie back either to Shelley's Frankenstein thematically or to
the imagery of Boris Karloff's rendition of the character on screen.
Frankenstein's Monster is a retelling of the cultural Golem myth.
This list does not include creatures more directly inspired by The
Golem, but focuses on those that Shelley's novel inspired.
Not all undead characters are versions of Frankenstein, as they fall
into other categories of Reanimation such as a Zombie.
The film explores themes of holiday, christmas party, santa
claus, christmas tree, saving christmas.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.